<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Eren Türkoglu</title><description/><link>https://erenworld.github.io/</link><item><title>On working at startup</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/startup/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/startup/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;Focus on one company&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn all about them. Read their blog. See what they are currently working on. For example, on the Cloudflare blog, you can see how they solve their problems.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/how-we-found-a-bug-in-gos-arm64-compiler/&quot;&gt;How we found a bug in Go’s ARM64 compiler&lt;/a&gt;. Each engineer writes about their approach to solving a problem. Contact those engineers. Solve problems for them. Improve their open-source codebase. Make a pull request. Don’t use AI. Show your real skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Minimal Neovim setup from scratch</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/neovim/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/neovim/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;Focus on one company&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn all about them. Read their blog. See what they are currently working on. For example, on the Cloudflare blog, you can see how they solve their problems.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/how-we-found-a-bug-in-gos-arm64-compiler/&quot;&gt;How we found a bug in Go’s ARM64 compiler&lt;/a&gt;. Each engineer writes about their approach to solving a problem. Contact those engineers. Solve problems for them. Improve their open-source codebase. Make a pull request. Don’t use AI. Show your real skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Show them how much you want to work for them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell them, (in your own way), “You are my favorite company. It’s my dream to work for you. If you have any aspect that could use a little help, let me do it, and I promise you it’ll thrive. I’m that passionate about this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Be Extraordinary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumes are boring. What really stands out is when someone is extraordinary.
Build a personal brand on a very specific niche. Be like the expert of the field. Post daily on X. Build side projects who shows what you are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Be persistent (though succinct)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine phone, email, and in-person. You must use all three methods, since each has its strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always be succinct. Don’t take more than two minutes of their time. But always show your passion, and how much you can help them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do this every week. It’s OK to be almost annoying. Polite manners don’t prove passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Do this until hired&lt;/h4&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How to get hired</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/get-hired/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/get-hired/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h4&gt;Focus on one company&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn all about them. Read their blog. See what they are currently working on. For example, on the Cloudflare blog, you can see how they solve their problems.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/how-we-found-a-bug-in-gos-arm64-compiler/&quot;&gt;How we found a bug in Go’s ARM64 compiler&lt;/a&gt;. Each engineer writes about their approach to solving a problem. Contact those engineers. Solve problems for them. Improve their open-source codebase. Make a pull request. Don’t use AI. Show your real skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Show them how much you want to work for them&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell them, (in your own way), “You are my favorite company. It’s my dream to work for you. If you have any aspect that could use a little help, let me do it, and I promise you it’ll thrive. I’m that passionate about this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Be Extraordinary&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resumes are boring. What really stands out is when someone is extraordinary.
Build a personal brand on a very specific niche. Be like the expert of the field. Post daily on X. Build side projects who shows what you are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Be persistent (though succinct)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combine phone, email, and in-person. You must use all three methods, since each has its strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always be succinct. Don’t take more than two minutes of their time. But always show your passion, and how much you can help them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do this every week. It’s OK to be almost annoying. Polite manners don’t prove passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Do this until hired&lt;/h4&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Cool Things #1</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/ct-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/ct-1/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://thorstenball.com/&quot;&gt;Thorsten Ball&lt;/a&gt; to share my own form of &lt;a href=&quot;https://registerspill.thorstenball.com/t/joy-and-curiosity&quot;&gt;joy and curiosity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mo42.bearblog.dev/read-to-forget/&quot;&gt;Read to Forget&lt;/a&gt; - I read a lot, and always find myself sometimes shuffling around to remember the details. But I like this frame of thinking, and it reminds me of how I&apos;ve been reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nassim_Nicholas_Taleb&quot;&gt;Taleb&apos;s&lt;/a&gt; books by letting the thoughts marinade in my head over a long period instead of highlighting everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stopa.io/post/297&quot;&gt;iPhone dumbphone&lt;/a&gt; - one of my favourite blogs, writing a post on something I love: people trying to make their phone use more intentional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleu-de-chauffe.com/en/&quot;&gt;bleu de chauffe&lt;/a&gt; - some beautiful bags and accessories made in France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fontsinuse.com/&quot;&gt;Fonts in use&lt;/a&gt; - I searched up a font and stumbled on this, nice mood board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seangoedecke.com/the-simplest-thing-that-could-possibly-work/&quot;&gt;Do the simplest thing that could possibly work&lt;/a&gt; - I try to think this way when building systems, but it&apos;s actually much harder in practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chillphysicsenjoyer.substack.com/p/youre-a-slow-thinker-now-what&quot;&gt;You&apos;re a Slow Thinker. Now what?&lt;/a&gt; - I think I&apos;m a mix of both a fast and slow thinker. I think fast in social interactions, but I struggle with quick mathematics on the spot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hope you enjoyed! do share anything you&apos;ve stumbled on recently.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>I added email subscriptions</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/email-subs/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/email-subs/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Great news for the 2 other people who read my blog – you can now read my posts via email!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried using &lt;a href=&quot;https://eren.substack.com/&quot;&gt;Substack&lt;/a&gt; as a way to just get my posts in peoples inboxes, but I didn&apos;t like how decoupled it was from my personal website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t like the idea of my posts lazily being posted around the internet, I want them to be in one canonical place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://buttondown.com/&quot;&gt;Buttondown&lt;/a&gt;, I have a solution that should hopefully be less friction to send and easier to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all it took:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;form
	action=&quot;https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/eren&quot;
	method=&quot;post&quot;
	target=&quot;_blank&quot;
&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;input
	type=&quot;email&quot;
	name=&quot;email&quot;
	required
  /&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;button type=&quot;submit&quot;&amp;gt;
   Subscribe
  &amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/form&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;d like to be one of the first subscribers, then please do share your email at the bottom of this post. It would truly mean a lot to me, and I hope to provide value for your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However if you&apos;re like me and also enjoy using an RSS reader (I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://netnewswire.com/&quot;&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt;), then you can stay updated by following my &lt;a href=&quot;rss.xml&quot;&gt;ATOM feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>How to grow a network from scratch (especially when you&apos;re young)</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/grow-network/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/grow-network/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In high school, I read my first book: &lt;em&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/em&gt; by Dale Carnegie.&lt;br /&gt;
Early on, I learned the immense value of building a strong network especially from scratch, with complete strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also went hand in hand with realizing that having a referral (at least in the tech industry) greatly increases the chances of your application being considered, since it literally lands right in a recruiter’s lap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m now 21, and over the past four years, I feel like I&apos;ve built a pretty strong network especially for someone who started with zero connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only am I &quot;connected&quot; with some fascinating people, but I’ve also built genuine friendships with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, in this short post, I’ll be sharing a few thoughts on how you can get your foot in the door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re young, ambitious, and somewhat outgoing, I hope this will be valuable to you. I definitely wish I had read something like this a few years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t some magical “hack” or manipulation tactic, I’m just someone who’s learned how to connect with people from all walks of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;In this post:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find people similar to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be curious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being young lets you off the hook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Find people similar to you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents are Turkish, and I’ve always been aware of how talented and diverse we are when it comes to producing engineering talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, I initially reached out to other Turks, since they were often more willing to help out one of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not part of a tight knit culture, that’s totally fine, it just means you’ll have fewer obvious things to connect on, but it’s not a disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Be curious&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One mistake many people make is sending a generic message like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey, how’s it going? I graduated from X and I’m applying for Y — could you give me a referral?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think that sounds uninspired and you’d be right but you’d be surprised how many messages like that people actually receive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember: &lt;strong&gt;you don’t know this person.&lt;/strong&gt; Show them why they should care about you and your story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I did was reach out to people whose background genuinely intrigued me maybe they built a cool project, had an interesting career path, or worked at a company I admired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless details you can pick up on their website, résumé, LinkedIn profile and use as a natural entry point to start a real conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind: most people get dozens of cold messages asking for referrals. Don’t be one more line in their inbox that sounds like everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Being young lets you off the hook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t mean this as an excuse to do dumb stuff and say “it’s fine, I’m young.”&lt;br /&gt;
But being young &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; give you room to take chances and make mistakes and people are usually more forgiving about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you’re in your early 20s, you have nothing to lose by reaching out to strangers. In fact, it’s the best time to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve asked some pretty naive questions in the past, but people often found it endearing partly because of my age and curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I noticed: reaching out to people 30+ can be surprisingly effective.&lt;br /&gt;
Once they reach a senior level, many feel it’s time to “pay it forward” to the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>On Watching Films Alone</title><link>https://erenworld.github.io/films-alone/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://erenworld.github.io/films-alone/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I watch a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterboxd.com/erenworld/&quot;&gt;films&lt;/a&gt;... not as much as I wish but a good amount to say that I think it&apos;s so much more enjoyable watching movies alone in the theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can really immerse in the filmmakers world, since you don&apos;t have to worry about making comments to your friends next to you. I can just let loose and let the film take me away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/don-cinema.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
(pic of me watching films alone)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean yeah you get some loud people in the theatre, but in general I watch films that attracts the type of crowd who appreciates the art of cinema, so are pretty respectful about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&apos;m romanticising cinema, but most of my favourite films were watched alone. I just love it so much, so I look forward to the day I could take my child to the cinema for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&apos;s also worth mentioning not every film is fun to watch by yourself, there are films made to be watched with friends. I have so many priceless memories from those films, even the shitty ones I&apos;ve watched at home on the TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a lot of people are surprised to hear when I say I&apos;m watching a film alone, but I think it&apos;s generally because people are just not comfortable with their own presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so if you&apos;ve never done it before, I suggest you give it a go, it&apos;ll be a fun experience, and you&apos;ll probably meet some cool people!&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>